Guide to the Marcus Cunliffe papers, 1960-1990 MS0125.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Conferences, lectures, seminars, symposia, 1957-1989; MS0125 Series 3; 2 Linear feet (Box 14, Box 13, Box 17, Box 16, Box 15)
  - Symposia, Etc.: "Lessons from the Fall and Rise of Nations" - presentations from Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Library of Congress Symposium on the American Revolution, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Symposia, Etc.: National Archives symposium, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Property colloquium - articles papers, 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Property colloquium - correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Property colloquium, 03/1983 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Symposium - Miracle of Virginia: The Role of American Leadership 1765-1789, Charlottesville, VA, 04/26/1982-04/27/1982 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Symposia, Etc.: Yorktown symposium -- Battle bicentennial, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Professional writing and consulting, 1947-1990; MS0125 Series 4; 4.5 Linear feet (Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 18)
  This series consists of Cunliffe's writing and consultant work. This includes his involvement with a film treatment of Thomas Jefferson and Alexander Hamilton, articles he wrote for magazines and journals such as Journal of American Studies, Smithsonian magazine, and contributions to books including the Encyclopedia of American Biography. This series also includes book reviews done by Cunliffe and reviews of his work.
  - American Council of Learned Societies' Guggenheim Fellowship for Cunliffe's book about the "Great Popular Author,", 1984-1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - American Media Center -- Hamilton/Jefferson film grant project, 1986-1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - American Media Center -- Hamilton/Jefferson film grant project, 1986-1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - American Media Center -- Hamilton/Jefferson film project - grant application planning, 4/01/1987-10/30/1987 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - American Media Center -- Hamilton/Jefferson film working document, 11/1987 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - American Media Center -- Hamilton/Jefferson film project- NEH application draft and film treatment draft by Tim Hackler, 1988 ca. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - American Media Center -- Hamilton/Jefferson film project- film treatment rough draft by Tim Hackler, 08/09/1988 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Article "American Watersheds" by Cunliffe and other notes, 1961 ca. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Article by Cunliffe "George Washington: Real and Symbolic Hero" for the American Constitutional Bicentennial Project, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Article by Cunliffe for U.S. News and World Report, Sept., 1981 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Article by Cunliffe on Harvard University for Encounter magazine and notes, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Article on property for the Encyclopedia of American Government and Politics, 1985 ca. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Articles for Smithsonian magazine written by Cunliffe, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "British Press Council" - paper by Cunliffe (with letter from Henry Luce) and clippings, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Chapter on property by Cunliffe in Encyclopedia of American Political History, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Commencement committee, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence on the Festschrift (anniversary publication), 1985-1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's comments on Fairfax County, Virginia, 04/1983 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's "American Thought" in The United States: A Companion to American Studies, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's "American Thought" in The United States: A Companion to American Studies, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Cunliffe's "Invention of the Presidency" in The Great Ideas Today, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Cunliffe's "Problems and Tendencies in American Studies" appearing in American Studies in Spain, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Cunliffe's "The Anatomy of Anti-Americanism" in Anti-Americanism in Europe, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Cunliffe's "The Two Georges: The President and the King" in American Studies International, 10/1986 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Cunliffe's application for NEH summer seminars, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Cunliffe's article "Backward Glances," in the Journal of American Studies, 04/1980 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Cunliffe's article "Crvecoeur Revisited" in Journal of American Studies, 08/1975 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Cunliffe's article "Frances Trollope, 1780-1863" in Abroad in America, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Cunliffe's article "How Independence was Finally Won" in Smithsonian magazine, 09/1983 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's article "Newness as Repudiation: Styles in American Thought," appearing in the Times Literary Supplement (TLS), 05/30/1980 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's article "Parson Weems and George Washington's Cherry Tree" from the Bulletin of John Rylands' Library, 11/1962 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's article "Proud to be a Redcoat" in the Observer, 08/03/1975 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's article "Teaching United States History Abroad: Great Britain" in The History Teacher, 11/1984 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's article "What If" for American Heritage, 12/1982 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's article for Smithsonian magazine - "The National Symbol Named George Washington,", 02/1982 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's article on "Anti-Communism,", 1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Cunliffe's articles for American Biographical Encyclopedia, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Cunliffe's articles for Sunday Telegraph, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Cunliffe's articles for the Boston Globe for the Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "American Thought" from The United States: A Companion to American Studies, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "Elections of 1789 and 1792" in History of American Elections, 1789-1968, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "George Washington's Generalship" in George Washington's Generals, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "New World, Old World: The Historian's Antithesis" from Lessons from America: An Exploration, 1974 (used in Transatlantic Essays, 1990), undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "The American Military Tradition" in The Americans:, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "The Condition of an American Literature" in American Literature to 1900, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "The Development of American Education," in American Civilization, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "The Two or More Worlds of Willa Cather" in The Art of Willa Cather, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "They Will all Speak English" in Peace and the Peacemakers, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Cunliffe's chapter "What Gracious God is Man?" in Portrait of America, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Cunliffe's comments on Manchester, England and North/South differences, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Cunliffe's contribution on "Property" to the Encyclopedia of American Political History - drafts, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Cunliffe's contribution on Daniel Webster in "I'd Wish I'd Been There" article in American Heritage, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Cunliffe's contribution to Burke's Presidential Families book, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Cunliffe's contribution to Sunday Times series on men and women who shaped the 20th century, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Cunliffe's contributions to Encyclopedia of American Biography (Lee, Poe, Washington), 1974 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Cunliffe's essay "The Cultural Patrimony of the United States,", 1984 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's essay on Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. in Pastmasters book, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's introduction "George Washington" for National Museum of American History catalog, 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's introduction for exhibit catalogue on George Washington in Washington state, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's introduction to reprint of John Marshall's George Washington, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's introduction to reprint of Woodrow Wilson's George Washington, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's introduction to The Divided Loyalist: Crevecoeur's America, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's opinion piece "America and Nixon" for Daily Mail, 08/07/1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "About America,", 1948 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "America's Imaginary Wars,", 05/1984 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "Henry Adams: An American Historian," Yale University, 04/1948 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "Is the Presidency a Monarchy?", 1980 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "Mark Twain and His English Novels," appearing in Times Literary Supplement (TLS), 12/25/1981 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "Peace of Paris" for Smithsonian Magazine, 07/20/1983 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "Private Property and American Independence" for American Association for State and Local History, 09/24/1982 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "Race Relations in the Union of South Africa and in the Southern States of USA,", 1955 ca. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The Cultural Patrimony of the United States,", 01/1984 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The Earth Belongs to the Living: Thomas Jefferson and the Limits of Inheritance,", 1982 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The George Washington Scandals,", 1982 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The Great Evasion: Treatments of Class and Race by 19th Century Americans,", 10/1984 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The House of Seven Gables" for Hawthorne Centenary Essays, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The Intellectuals: The United States,", undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The Invention of the Presidency,", 03/1987 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The United States: 1783-1865,", 01/1983 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Cunliffe's paper - "The Widening and Weakening of Republicanism in Nineteenth-Century America" for American Historical Association conference, Washington, DC, 12/1982 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Cunliffe's paper and draft notes "Formative Features: From Columbus to World War I,", 02/1985 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Cunliffe's proposal for NEH Summer Seminar research, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's talk on Matthew Arnold aired on BBC radio, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Edinburgh Humanities Institute, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Essay "America's Imaginary Wars" for book In Search of America, 1984-1986 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Essays for book In Search of America, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Festschrift" project, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Four Cunliffe essays, 1955-1982 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Grant proposal from The Library of America for series of biographies on famous Americans, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Harriet Beecher Stowe's Eliza television project, including screenplay, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Program, Washington, DC workshop, 11/13/1983-11/19/1983 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - J.G.A. Pocock's proposed Folger Center for the history of British political thought, 1981-1984 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Leavey Foundation Awards, 1984-1985 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript for "The British Army as an Institution" by Marcus Cunliffe, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) "Concept of the Heroic" project, 1984-1985 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Northern Virginia Heritage magazine, 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Notes for Cunliffe's American Literature, History and life, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Notes for Harvard survey course 61B, Spring Term, 1947-1959 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - Agriculture and the Role of Government, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - Finance Capitalism and the Federal Reserve System, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - Government and the Economy: Prospects for the Future, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - National Labor Relations Act, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - National Planning in World War I, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - National Recovery Administration, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - The Chicago Strike of 1894, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - The Money Question, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - The Pure Food and Drugs Act and Meat Inspection Regulations, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Notes for History 20 class at Yale University - The Standard Oil Company, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Notes for lecture "Fictional Visions of Future Wars," Mar. 18 [no year], undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - OBIS book -- Creators and Thinkers, v.10, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - OBIS book -- Progressivism, v.11, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Paper - "Henry Adams: An American Historian," by Marcus Cunliffe (Yale University class), 1948 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Organization of American Historians -- notes, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Paper by Cunliffe - "The George Washington Scandals" and photostats of Washington images, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Paper by Cunliffe "The Lottery Principle and the United States" and notes on lotteries, 1978-1990 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Project '87 - The American Constitutional Bicentennial, 1981-1984 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Projects - general, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for seminar The Great Popular Author in Britain and the United States (1800-1915), 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Resumes for Otto Salgo Visiting Professorship, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Resumes for Otto Salgo Visiting Professorship, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Resumes of Marcus Cunliffe, 1981-1988 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Society of American Historians, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Submission for The World and I magazine, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago radio discussion with Cunliffe - "Is Our Visa Policy Hurting Us?", 09/21/1952 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Various articles by Cuniffe, 1954-1969 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Book reviews by and about Cunliffe, 1968-1988 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Book reviews by Cunliffe, 1955-1968 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Book reviews by Cunliffe, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Book reviews by Cunliffe, 1983-1986 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Book reviews by Cunliffe, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's book reviews for the for the Washington Post, 1980-1987 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's book reviews for The Listener, 1952-1955 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's book reviews for the Manchester Guardian, 1952-1976 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Cunliffe's book reviews for the New Republic, 1979-1981 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Cunliffe's book reviews for the New Statesman, 1951-1961 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Cunliffe's book reviews for the Spectator, 1961-1967 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Cunliffe's book The Martial Spirit in America, 1775-1865 - reviews, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Cunliffe's comments on Abraham Lincoln, 09/1984 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Cunliffe's comments on teaching United States history abroad (Great Britain), undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Cunliffe's critique of Bernard Schwarz' book George Washington: Symbol for an Age, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Cunliffe's miscellaneous book reviews, 1949-1967 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Cunliffe's miscellaneous book reviews, 1949-1967 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Cunliffe's review "From the Facts to the Feelings," (psychohistory of George A. Custer and Henry Adams) appearing in Times Literary Supplement (TLS), 10/23/1981 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Cunliffe's review "The Historian's Turf" appearing in the Washington Post, 08/1981 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Cunliffe's review "The Yankee Demothenes" (Daniel Webster) appearing in the Times Literary Supplement (TLS), 09/17/1976 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Cunliffe's review of "The Autobiography of Benjamin Franklin" for New York Herald Tribune, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Cunliffe's review of American Literature, 1912-1932 by John McCormick, 06/05/1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Cunliffe's review of More Die of Heartbreak by Saul Bellow, 05/1987 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Cunliffe's review of Quest for Immortality: A Theory of Abraham Lincoln's Political Psychology, by Dwight Anderson, 09/1984 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe's review of Soviet view of George Washington in American Heritage, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Cunliffe's reviews of books for New York Times Book Review, 1963-1965 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Cunliffe's review of The Old Devils by Kingsley Amis in Washington Times, 03/16/1987 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Cunliffe's review of Tuchman's March of Folly, 03/1984 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Cunliffe's reviews and articles, 1965-1981 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Cunliffe's reviews for Encounter, 1955-1964 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Cunliffe's reviews for New Statesman, 1957-1973 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Cunliffe's reviews for the New York Times, 1981-1984 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Cunliffe's reviews for the New York Times, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Cunliffe's reviews of books for New York Times Book Review, 1963-1965 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Cunliffe's solicited evaluation of article submitted to William and Mary Quarterly, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Cunliffe's review of T.V. program "Orphan's of the Storm,", 1990 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Notes and reviews of William Bullitt and Sigmund Freud's book on Woodrow Wilson, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Review by Cunliffe for American Quarterly, 1985-1990 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Review by Cunliffe - "America and the Pattern of Chivalry" in the Journal of American History, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Review of The Shaping of America in William and Mary Quarterly Review, 07/1981 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Reviews and articles about Marcus Cunliffe's work - news clippings, 1953-1958 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Reviews and articles by Marcus Cunliffe - news clippings, 1952-1958 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Reviews for Times Literary supplement, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Reviews of Cunliffe's George Washington: Man and Monument, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Reviews of Cunliffe's work - clippings, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Reviews of Chattel Slavery and Wage Slavery, 1983-1985 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Reviews of Cunliffe's book The Nation Takes Shape, 1789-1837 and correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Various book reviews by Cunliffe, 1955-1989 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - "American Continent" -- book chapter and notes, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - American Presidents and the Presidency book, revised edition - chapter drafts, etc., 1987 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Book cover for paperback edition of George Washington: Man and Monument, 1980 ca. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Book project on King George III, 1970-1976 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Book project on King George III, 1970-1976 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Bryce and Convergence - for chapter six of The Separate Republic book, 1889-1988 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Bryce and Convergence - for chapter six of The Separate Republic book, 1889-1988 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Liverpool University Press, 1977-1980 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and contracts for Cunliffe's George Washington: Man and Monument, 1954-1983 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and publishers agreement between Cunliffe and American Heritage Publishing Company on book American Presidents and the Presidency, 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 10)
- Cunliffe's book projects: notes, correspondence, and contracts, 1842-1990; MS0125 Series 5; 8.5 Linear feet (Box 45, Box 33, Box 34, Box 42, Box 35, Box 44, Box 43, Box 30, Box 29, Box 32, Box 31, Box 40, Box 41, Box 38, Box 39, Box 36, Box 37)
  This series consists of Cunliffes notes (including photocopied portions of books), drafts, and correspondence with publishers for many of the books and chapters to books he wrote. These include George Washington: Man and Monument, The Literature of the United States, Soldiers and Civilians, and Transatlantic Essays (published posthumously). The publisher's contract for George Washington is in Box 28.
  - Correspondence on book Pastmasters (essays on historians) edited by Cunliffe, 1985-1987 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Greenwood Press concerning Cunliffe's book In Search of America, 1983-1990 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Greenwood Press concerning Cunliffe's book In Search of America, 1983-1990 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Greenwood Press concerning final preparation of manuscript for In Search of America, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Harper and Row Publishers, 1984-1986 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Julian Bach, literary agent, 1984-1987 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with literary agent Christopher Busby, 1972-1975 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with McGraw-Hill Publishers, 1972-1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Penguin Books concerning Literature of the United States, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Penguin Books regarding a new edition of The Literature of the United States, 1982-1985 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Penguin Books regarding book Literature in the United States, 1985-1987 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with various publishers, 1981-1988 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - George Washington - notes, 1842-1983 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - George Washington - notes, 1858-1974 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - George Washington - notes, 1884-1982 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - George Washington - notes, 1886-1984 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - George Washington - notes, 1904-1979 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - George Washington - notes, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - George Washington - notes, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - George Washington - opinions of, 1889-1982 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - George Washington in sermons and obituaries, 1800 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - George Washington memorabilia - postcards, photos, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- Chapter 1: Washington Monument, 1952-1956 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- Chapter 2: George Washington Esquire, 1954-1956 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- Chapter 3: General George Washington, 1955-1956 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- Chapter 4: President Washington, 1954-1956 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- Chapter 5: The Whole Man, 1954-1956 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- general notes, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- notes and rough draft of chapter outlines, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - George Washington, Man and Monument book -- publisher's correspondence and articles, 1953-1961 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - George Washington: Man and Monument book - paperback book cover, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - George Washington's scandals, 1873-1982 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - George Washington's scandals, 1925-1982 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Harper book - notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - A History of the United States, 1787-1837 book- notes on the American character and memorandum of agreement with publisher, 1942-1957 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - A History of the United States, 1787-1837 book - notes on the American character, 1942-1957 (Box 31, Folder 15)